Contact

arjunbharat99@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/arjun-bharat-314b5518b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Software Development

C++

Java

Honors-Awards

National Standard Examination in Physics (NSEP)

National Standard Examination in Chemistry (NSEC)

National Standard Examination in Astronomy (NSEA)

Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana(KVPY)

Indian National Physics Olympiad (InPhO)

Arjun Bharat

Software Engineering Intern at DE Shaw|Former Software Engineering Internship at Motorq | Aditya Birla Scholar '17 | JEE Advanced AIR 26

Chennai

Summary

I am an enthusiastic and dedicated individual with a keen interest in Computer Science and Mathematics. My main interests are Data Structures, Algorithms, Compiler Design, and Automata Theory. I am currently pursuing a research project on Compiler Design under the guidance of my professor and with industrial collaboration. I have done coursework on other areas of Computer Science such as Machine Learning and Graph Theory, and Management Studies as well.

I enjoy being part of a team and contributing to ideas and impact making decisions. I have interned in the domain of Financial Technology as well as product-based companies.

Experience

Shaastra, IIT Madras

2 years 3 months

Events Core

April 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- Leading a team of 11 heads and over 110 coordinators to organise events aimed at promoting technological innovation, research, and subject knowledge across India.
- Currently leading the publishing of a tri-weekly blog on science and technology for school and college students, called Techshots.
- Currently planning the organization of a pan India technical festival for school students called Ignite, scheduled to take place in September.

Events Head, Coding and Logic May 2019 - March 2020 (11 months)

Chennai Area, India

- Lead a team of 17 coordinators and 36 volunteers to organise a total of 13 events in Shaastra 2020: an addition of 5 new events compared to the previous edition.
- Organised events with a total budget of around INR 600000, more than double the previous edition.
- Initiated and executed a plan to distribute customized T-shirts for five events across India thereby increasing Shaastra's brand name and credibility.
- Organised and oversaw the execution of 4 Industry-sponsored Hackathons and a workshop on Deep Learning.
- Organised 8 events relating to various domains of coding and puzzle-based events.

Event Coordinator

June 2018 - April 2019 (11 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- Prepared problems for and organized a nation-wide programming contest on Codechef which saw the participation of more than 800 teams across India.
- Came up with a new initiative to distribute T-shirts across India to nationwide finalists.

The D. E. Shaw Group

Software Engineer

May 2020 - June 2020 (2 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana

- Worked as a software developer intern in the quantitative trading team with a focus on energy commodities.
- Worked on Monte Carlo simulations using Python for options and futures contracts to estimate the portfolio risk.
- Worked on the visualization of price distributions of options and futures and studied their variations.
- The APIs for risk computation were moved to firmwide production shortly afterward.

Motorq

Software Engineer

June 2019 - July 2019 (2 months)

Chennai Area, India

 Upgraded the documentation from Swagger 2.0 to OpenAPI Specification 3.0, to allow for an expanded query pattern in the query API used by customers.

- Performed extensive load tests on TimescaleDB, the time series extension to PostgreSQL using asynchronous programming in JavaScript.
- Tested the emerging distributed database CitusDB by simulating parallel data consumption and production mechanisms.

Saarang

Event Coordinator

April 2018 - April 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- Organised speaking events at Saarang 2019, the cultural festival of IIT Madras. Witnessed an increase in participation of over 1.5x compared to the previous years.
- Organized workshops on debating and public speaking throughout the semester.

Centre For Innovation (CFI)

Coordinator

April 2018 - April 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- Organized institute-wide programming contests to further the spirit of competitive programming.
- Instructed sessions on advanced Data Structures during the summer school on programming.
- Maintained a blog on basic algorithms to educate freshers on programming.

Inter IIT Sports Meet

Committee Member

September 2017 - December 2017 (4 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

- Organized badminton matches among talented sportsperson from IITs across India, across a week-long sports festival.
- The only freshman to be a part of the organizing team of 2017.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science · (2017 - 2021)

National Institute of Open Schooling

12th Standard · (2015 - 2017)

Sishya 10th Standard · (2002 - 2015)